QUALITY ASSURANCE ENGINEER, & PRODUCT MANAGER

Career Overview

Over 7 years of varied experience in the IT industry. Experience with End to End delivery of products . Verify and sign off on all functionality. Experience and knowledge in Agile workflow . Use Agile methodologies to ensure project is executed to meet deadlines. Experience in eliciting requirements and documenting them. Experience in effectively coordinating and communicating with offshore teams . Experience in release activities for products in both the iTunesConnect and Google play store . Experience with implementing test strategy for Multiplatform apps. Experience testing a multiplatform product. Experience with implementing Automation Testing Framework for iOS and Android mobile apps . Extensive experience in manual Black box testing Moderate Experience in product and project management. Experience in working with a multiplatform app. Experience in Development and Testing of User interfaces and Websites. Extensive client interaction and coordination exposure. Knowledge of software development methodologies with involvement in most stages of SDLC. Able to study new technologies and tricky concepts rapidly and execute them. Outstanding analytical, decision-making, problem solving and management skills with the ability to organize activities in fast speedy team environment. Ability to perform effectively and efficiently in team and individually.

Qualifications

- Operating Systems
- Windows NT
- Languages & Technology
- Java, C, XML, XSL, JSP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP
- Databases
- Oracle 9i, Microsoft Access, SQL
- Tools & Utilities
- Eclipse, Edit Plus, TOAD 7.4.0.1, Microsoft Office Suite Products, Magic Draw, IBM Rational ClearCase, CVS, Site Manager, E-publish, TOAD8, JIRA
- Server
- IDOL Server7, Tomcat, Websphere

Accomplishments

- Trained on Business and Requirements Engineering Trained on C, Java, J2EE, Oracle 9i, D2K and XML.
- Trained on OS Concepts.
- Trained on SSAD and OOAD with UML.
- Attended Proposal writing workshop.

Work Experience

Quality Assurance Engineer,& Product Manager

May 2012 to January 2016 Detroit, MI

- Project and Product Management Analyse and write requirements for both Android and iOS apps.
- Communicate and Coordinate with the stake holders, UX designers, Offshore and Onsite Engineers and QA to make sure the project runs smoothly and the deadlines are met.
- Sign off on every functionality.
- Manage development and delivery of multiple apps on the iOS and Android platforms.
- Review and prioritize bugs and issues raised by the QA team to ensure progress of the project.
- Submit builds for beta testing.
- Perform all the release activities and make sure a release build is submitted to the respective app store.
- Quality Assurance Review bug reports to ensure good quality bugs are written and reported Review test cases written by QA team.
- · Implementing Test Strategies and test plans.
- Sign off on functionalities Creating and editing test cases for iOS and Android apps.
- Test Case management using tools like Aptest manager.
- Implementing an automation-testing framework called Frank for iOS mobile apps.
- Extensive manual Black box testing for iOS and Android mobile apps Unit, Integration and Regression Testing.
- Issue management and Tracking using tools like jira and fogbugz.
- Business Analysis Requirement Gathering from clients and Subject matter experts.
- Validate and Analyze the requirements through JAD sessions.
- Developed use cases and use case diagrams based on the requirements gathered.
- Use Case documentation for reengineering a working application.
- Extensive interaction with clients throughout the projects.
- Development Enhanced and improved the usability of a business search portal.
- Developed user interfaces for search applications.
- Worked at fine tuning and implementing enhanced search capabilities of IDOL server.
- Developed web sites for content management and information dissemination using a tool.
- Was responsible for the maintenance and support of many of the major websites of World Bank.
- Clients Worked With Human Capital Development Logitech IFC (International Finance Corporation) The World Bank BRANCHFIRE is a Chicago-based productivity software company that is reinventing the way people consume and create digital content.
- Our first product is the critically-acclaimed application iAnnotate PDF, which counts more than 600,000 users worldwide, comprising students, educators, lawyers, accountants, and other professionals.

- Branchfire launched a multi-platform POC product called Folia in July 2014.
- In March 2015 Branchfire restructured to keep up with demands of it customer and is now coming out with a cross platform collaboration app that can cater to the needs of both the consumer and the enterprise market.
- Contribution Responsible for making product level decisions.
- Responsible for assigning work and ensuring completion of assigned activities.
- Coordinate with stake holders, design Engineering and QA resources to ensure correct requirements have been implemented Responsible for tracking and verifying requirements and defects.
- Responsible for product sign off.
- Was part of the reorganizing and restructuring process to form an effective team.
- Coordinate with design/ Responsible for all the release level activities for the Product.
- Was responsible for the overall quality of the folia products delivered on iOS, Android ,Windows and Mac Solely responsible for conducting Manual Black box testing for the PDF App iAnnotate on both iOS and Android mobile platforms.
- Researched and implemented an automation testing framework for the iOS version of iAnnotate.
- Researched and Implemented a new and efficient test case management system called Aptest manager.
- Responsible for providing sign off for the product before app submission.
- Responsible for performing Regression Testing on the mobile app for every release cycle.

Web Designer

November 2008 to December 2008 Austin, TX

- Analysis of the existing functionality of the system.
- Identifying new requirements based on responses and reviews of the portal and by interacting with Subject Matter Experts.
- Developing User Interface prototypes based on usability guidelines.
- Enhancing and improving the design of the web interface, layouts and site graphics.
- Incorporating web usability standards in the user interface.
- Performing Black Box and Regression Testing on the application.

Software Engineer

March 2004 to April 2008 Satyam Computer Services Limited

- Projects Worked On Logitech Autonomy Knowledge Management Portal (LogiFind) is an enterprise wide knowledge management portal
 which captures user attention with intuitive results, enhanced user experience and adaptability Contribution Requirements Gathering from
 subject matter experts.
- Was an Integral part of the brain storming session and requirement feasibility study.
- Use Case development based on the high level requirement gathered.
- Analysis and study of the existing application in order to enable smooth sailing integration of the new interface.
- Developing the User Interface of the application.
- Configuration of the IDOL Server to incorporate all the advanced search functionalities of Autonomy.
- Unit and Integration testing of the application.
- Successful implementation and integration of phase 1 of the search project.
- Expertise Locator Contribution Requirement Gathering from senior managers and HR.
- Analysis and feasibility study of the requirement.
- Configuration of the IDOL Server to achieve functionalities such as Hyper-linking, Parametric refinement, Legacy Search and User defined search.
- Studying the existing portals of Autonomy (Portal-in-a-box & Retina) and developing a customized portal for Satyam.
- Online SBI Online SBI is a transaction portal developed for the SBI to enable the customers to transact online.
- Contribution Study and Analysis of the existing system by reading documents and conducting functionality testing.
- Develop effective use cases and draw Business Process Diagrams.
- Analysis of the new requirements and check feasibility.
- Make necessary updates to the use cases and Business Process Diagrams.
- iDESK Reengineering Use case Documentation for IFC Contribution Study and Analysis of the existing system by reading documents and conducting functionality testing.
- Interact with the clients for inputs and clarifications Develop Use cases for all the existing functionalities that were assigned.
- Coordinating with the development team and reviewers to produce quality use cases.
- Preparation of use cases adhering to IFC standards.
- Interact with clients for Use Case sign off.
- Complete ownership of the developed use cases.
- The Internet Services Program (ISP) is a project to upgrade the internet of The World Bank.
- Contribution Analysis of the specifications provided by the clients.
- Requirement clarifications and suggestions for improvement to the requirements given by the client.
- Client Interaction.
- Design and Development of websites.
- Configuration of these websites using the tool Site manager.
- Testing unit testing & integration testing Responsible for overseeing the Quality procedures related to the project.
- Responsible for Bug fixing & Enhancements to the delivered modules.
- It involves End to End Responsibility.

Education and Training

Bachelor of Technology: Civil Engineering, July 2003 Cochin University India Civil Engineering

automation, Business Analysis, Business Process, C, Case management, ClearCase, content, content management, Draw, CSS, client, Clients, Client Interaction, CVS, Databases, delivery, Documentation, Eclipse, editing, Edit, XML, feasibility study, Finance, graphics, UX, HTML, HR, PHP, IBM, ISP, Internet Services, Java, JSP, JavaScript, Knowledge Management, knowledge management, Mac, Magic, market, Microsoft Access, Microsoft Office Suite, Windows, Windows NT, enterprise, Operating Systems, Oracle 9, PDF, Product Management, progress, Quality, QA, Quality Assurance, reading, Reengineering, Requirement, Requirements Gathering, SQL, TOAD8, TOAD 7.4.0, Tomcat, upgrade, User Interface, Utilities, web sites, websites, Websphere, written, XSL